Southwest Folklore Center Sound Disc Collection, 1945-1987
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- El Conjunto Murrietta: Tocando norteno, El Conjunto Murrietta, 1978; Phoenix AZ., Canyon Records, p1978; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Performed by El Conjunto Murrietta... Richard Murrietta, guitar and vocals; Robert Hernandez, bass and vocals; Johnny Murrietta, accordion; Sammy Gastelum, drums... Prieta linda -- Uwaldina y Juan Gonzales -- Ritmo mambo -- Angel de mi gloria -- Que bonito -- La buenota -- Quiero ver -- Flor del campo -- El borrachito -- Pilares de cristal -- Borracho fue tequilero -- Mis brazos de esparan --; SWF 87.12/D.48 (12in.)
- The Cisco Band, The Cisco Band, 1975; Phoenix AZ., Canyon Records, p1975; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Performed by The Cisco Band... Francis "Cisco" Enriquez, saxophone; Frank Joaquin, guitar; Leroy Martinez, bass; David Narcho, drums; Marvin Enis, accordion and guitar... Mountain chair -- Where were you last night -- Love of my life -- Why not -- Marsa -- Howabout Queenswell -- Trophy -- Did you see -- Felipe -- Who knows -- Like it was -- I remember --; SWF 87.12/D.49 (12in.)
- Gila River Six (Minus One): Pima chicken scratch from the Gila River, Gila River Six (Minus One), 1979; Phoenix AZ., Canyon Records, p1979; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Performed by the Gila River Six... Virgil Jose, accordion; Johhnie Kisto, sax; Elvey Whitman, guitar; Guy Schurz, bass guitar; Leonard Harrison, drums... San tan waltz -- Aw-aw-thum waila -- Hay mi Yaquicita cumbia -- Papago chote -- American polka -- Colorado River polka -- Ambicion waila -- La mucura cumbia -- El gavilan chote -- Manzana waila -- J. C. chote -- Sabor a mi bolero --; SWF 87.12/D.50 (12in.)
- Yaqui music of the pascola and deer dance, 1973; Phoenix, AZ., Canyon Records, 1973; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Recorded live during the Tiniran Fiesta at Potam, Rio Yaqui, Sonora, Mexico... Performed by Jose Maria Hupahe, violin; Chito Matus, harp; Juan Maria Valencia, drum and flute; Juan Cruz Valencia, deer dancer; Reynaldo Romero Matus, Manuel Alvarez, Manuel Lucero, pascolas; Guadalupe Flores, Luis Aldamas, Luis A. Valenzuela, deer singers... Cogui Yeka (pic nose) -- San Martin Manuelito -- Ta'ka Cho'nim (body hair) -- Yoh'Hopoli (Mother night bird) -- Loretta cantorata -- Ten'ku Ba'nim -- Tene Woi Yueria -- Kuu'ta Wi'Kuii (sung by Maso Buik'reom) -- Puchilai -- W. Rum (Buzzard) -- Canoa Moelata Mavetacamel (old boat) -- Cuncum (doves)(sung by Maso Buik'roem) -- Sotohmoela (old earthen pot) --; SWF 87.12/D.51 (12in.)
- Malo Katcina -- Pawik Katcina, Kutqa, Chief of Walpai Tribe, and Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpai Tribe, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Testing copy of Hopi katcina songs... Traditional Hopi songs made at the Grand Canyon in the 1920s... Pawik Katchina by Hungi, head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi tribe -- Duck ceremony and malo katcina --; SWF 87.13/D.1 (10in.)
- Tacab Katcina -- Homis Katcina, and Hungi, Hunaweu and KaKapti, Recorded on the Hopi Reservation; Produced by Gennett, Richmond, IN.; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Recorded on the Hopi Reservation... Made under the supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... [1920s]... Tacab Katcina (sung by Hunawen) -- Homis Katcina (sund by Ko' Kapti) --; SWF 87.13/D.2 (10in.)
- Chant of the eagle dance -- Chant of the snake dance, Hopi Indian Chanters, Camden, N.J., Radio Victor Corporation of America; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in., Orthophonic Recording; Traditional Hopi music recorded during the 1920s at the Grand Canyon... Chant of the snake dance (Hopi Indian charmers (group of M.W. Billingsley) -- Chant of the eagle dance --; SWF 87.13/D.3 (10in.)
- Musayazeu Katcina -- Puwamuy Katcina, Kutqa, Chief of Walpi Tribe of Hopi, and Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpai Tribe, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Traditional Hopi music recorded in the 1920s at Grand Canyon... test copy, see SWF 87.13/D.5... Puwamuy Katcina (by Hungi, head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi tribe) -- Bean harvest -- Musayazen Katcina (by Kutqa, Chief of the Walpi tribe of Hopi) -- Buffalo hunt --; SWF 87.13/D.4 (10in.)
- Puwa'muy Katcina (Bean harvest) -- Musayazeu Katcina (Buffalo hunt), Kutqa, Chief of Walpi Tribe of Hopi, and Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe, Recorded on the Hopi Reservation; Produced by Gennett, Richmond, IN.; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Puwa'muy Katcina (Bean harvest) sung by Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe -- Musayazeu Katcina (Buffalo hunt) sung by Kutqa, Chief of Walpi Tribe of Hopi...; SWF 87.13/D.5 (10in.)
- Anga Katcina (Beard dance) -- Tacheukta Katcina, KaKapti, Teuma'euy and Hunaweu, Chief Head of Snake Ceremony Walpi Tribe, Recorded on the Hopi Reservation; Produced by Gennett, Richmond, IN.; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Anga Katcina (Beard dance)(sung by Teuma'euy Kakapti) -- Tacheukta Katcina (sung by Hunaweu, Chief Head of Snake Ceremony Walpi Tribe)...; SWF 87.13/D.6 (10in.)
- Anga Katcina -- Tacheukta Katcina, KaKapti, Teuma'euy and Hunaweu, Chief Head of Snake Ceremony Walpi Tribe, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Test copy, see SWF 87.13/D.6... Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Anga Katcina (Beard dance)(sung by Teuma'euy Kakapti) -- Tacheukta Katcina (sung by Hunaweu, Chief Head of Snake Ceremony Walpi Tribe)...; SWF 87.13/D.7 (10in.)
- Suyuhim Katcina -- Maqutu (Rabbit hunt), Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe, and KaKapti, Recorded on the Hopi Reservation; Produced by Gennett, Richmond, IN.; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Suyuhim Katcina (Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe) -- Maqutu (Rabbit hunt) sung by KaKapti...; SWF 87.13/D.8 (10in.)
- Suyuhim Katcina -- Maqutu, Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe, and KaKapti, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Test copy, see SWF 87.13/D.8... Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Suyuhim Katcina (Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe) -- Maqutu (Rabbit hunt) sung by KaKapti...; SWF 87.13/D.9 (10in.)
- Awatawi (Entry song to the buffalo hunt) -- Nakeutawi - War dance - Victory, Hopi Indians, The Hopi House, Grand Canyon, Recorded at Grand Canyon National Park, AZ.; Produced by Gennett, Richmond, IN.; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Awatawi (Entry song to the buffalo hunt) -- Nakeutawi - War dance - Victory (Hopi Indians at the Hopi House, Grand Canyon; accompanied by tomtom, gourd rattles, etc.)...; SWF 87.13/D.10 (10in.)
- Awatawi -- Nakeutawi - War dance - Victory, Hopi Indians at the Hopi House, Grand Canyon, 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Test copy, see SWF 87.13/D.10... Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Awatawi (Entry song to the buffalo hunt) -- Nakeutawi - War dance - Victory (Hopi Indians at the Hopi House, Grand Canyon; accompanied by tomtom, gourd rattles, etc.)...; SWF 87.13/D.11 (10in.)
- Pawik Katcina (Duck ceremony) -- Malo Katcina, Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe, and Kutqa, Chief of Walpi Tribe of Hopi, Recorded on the Hopi Reservation; Produced by Gennett, Richmond, IN.; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, 1920s... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Pawik Katcina (Duck ceremony) Hungi, Head of Antelope Lodge, Walpi Tribe-- Malo Katcina (Kutqa, Chief of Walpi Tribe of Hopi)...; SWF 87.13/D.12 (10in.)
- Nakeutawi, Hopi Chanters, 1927; January 28, 1927; 1 sound disc, analog, 10 in.; Test copy, see SWF 87.13/D.10... Recorded at the Grand Canyon on the Hopi Reservation, Jan. 28, 1927... Made under supervision of Dr. J. Walter Fewkes, Chief of the Bureau of Ethnology, Smithsonian Institute, in cooperation with the Santa Fe and Fred Harvey... Nakeutawi - War dance - Victory (Hopi Indians at the Hopi House, Grand Canyon; accompanied by tomtom, gourd rattles, etc.)...; SWF 87.13/D.13 (10in.)
- Special delivery to you, Special delivery, Phoenix, AZ., Polka West Records; 1 sound disc, analog, 33 1/3 rpm, 12 in.; Performed by Special Delivery... Jim Warden, trumpet and vocals; Frank Dougal, clarinet, sax and second trumpet; Bob Jayo, drum and vocals; Bob Rosinski, accordion and vocals; Joe Tompkins, bass guitar and vocals... Apples -- Clarinet polka -- I love everybody -- Leezers oberek -- Oj dig a dig -- Where do the good times go -- Open up your heart -- Hupaj siu paj -- Four in the morning -- High bounce -- Tam pod krakowem -- Spending money --; SWF 88.4/D.1 (12in.)
- The Mexican Revolution: Record #1, Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog,[33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by various artists... Nuevo corrido de madero (Camacho and Perez) -- El Cuartelazo (Juanita and Maria Mendoza) -- Benjamin Argumedo (Morales and Romero) -- Fusilamiento de Felipe Angeles (San Roman and Vera) -- Ignacio Parra (Los Alegres de Teran) -- Valentin Mancera (Trio Los Aguilillas) -- Potroelobo gateado (Mariachi Mexico del Norte) -- Jesus Leal (Rocha and Martinez) -- Heraclio Bernal (Trio Nava) -- Benito Canales (Garcia and Guerrero) --; SWF 88.7/D.1 (12in.)
- The Mexican Revolution: Record #2, Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by various artists... La toma de celaya (Las Hermanos Banuelos) -- Derrota de villa en celaya (Rocha and Martinez) -- Rendicin de Pancho Villa (Rocha and Martinez) -- Historia y muerte de villa (More, Rubi and Vivo)-- Corrido de Durango (Los Dorados de Durango) -- Gral. Francisco Villa (Los Cuatezones) -- La Toma de Torreon (Los Alegres de Teran) -- La toma de Zacatecas (Los Errantes) -- La toma de Celaya (Conjunto Matamoros) -- Pancho Villa Los Hermanos Chavarria) -- La Punitiva (Hernandez and Sifuentes) -- La toma de Celaya (Los Hermanos Banuelos) -- Derrota de villa en Celaya (Rocha and Martinez) --; SWF 88.7/D.2 (12in.)
- The Mexican Revolution: Record #3, Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Music by various artists... Corrido de Juan Vasquez (Juanita and Maria Mendoza) -- Juan Carrasco (Luis Perez Mesa) -- Corrido de Palamon Ojeda (Los Montaneses del Alamo) -- Corrido de Juan Villareal (Los Hermanos Garza) -- La toma de Matamoros (Lara and Novelo) -- Corrido de almazan (Mendez and Gonzales) -- Amador Maldanaldo (Conjunto Tamaulipas) --; SWF 88.7/D.3 (12in.)
- The Mexican Revolution: Record #4, Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Music by various artists... Revolucion de Adolfo de la Huerta (Briceno and Anez) -- La pura pelada (Trio Luna) -- El Arreglo religioso (Duo Coahuila) -- La Nueva revolucion (San Roman and Vera) -- El Corrido del agrarista (Trovadores Tamaulipeus) -- General Obregon (Trio Luna) -- El radiograma (Guzman and Rosales) -- Corrido toral (Travadores Tapatios) -- General Emiliano Zapata (Trio Luna) -- Gral. Porfirio Diaz (Dueto Acosta) -- Tiempos Amargos (Dueto America) --; SWF 88.7/D.4 (12in.)
- Steve Jordan, Jordan, Steve, 1987; Arhoolie Productions, Inc., p1987; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by Steve Jordan... Las Corondas -- Estrella del norte -- Midnight blues -- Jamas volvere -- El Rancho grande -- El Corrido de Johnny el Pachuco -- La Pepita -- Vuela paloma -- Together again -- More pretty girls than one --; SWF 88.7/D.5 (12in.)
- Las Hermanas Mendoza: Juanita y Maria, Mendoza, Juanita and Maria Mendoza, Los Angeles, CA., Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by Las Hermanas Mendoza, Juanita and Maria... Mi Pensamiento -- Sone que me jurabas -- Algun dia -- Cada vez que me acuerdo -- Dos seres que si aman -- Que chula prieta -- Linda Morenita -- Los picones -- Manuelita -- Yo vivo en la pranda -- Pero Lupita -- Tu sentencia -- El Resbaloso -- El Desquite -- Por ani se dice --; SWF 88.7/D.6 (12in.)
- The Earliest Mariachi recordings, 1906-1938: Volume 1, [Los Angeles, CA.], Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by various Mariachi groups... Mariachi Coculense Rodriguez de Cirilo Marmolejo: El Toro -- El Gavilancillo -- El Durazno -- La Ensalada -- El Suchil -- El Jilguerillo -- El Cuervo -- Mariquita -- La Negra (Mariachi Tapatio) -- El Tirador (Mariachi Tapatio) -- La Primavera (Mariachi Tapatio) -- Eres la mas consentida (Mariachi Vargas) -- El Riflero (Mariachi Vargas) -- Serenata Ranchera (Mariachi Vargas de Tata Nacho) -- La Violinera (Mariachi Vargas de Tata Nacho) Los Abajenas (Cuarteto Coculense) --; SWF 88.7/D.7 (12in.)
- Mariachi Coculense de Cirilo Marmolejo, 1933-1936, Mariachi Coculense de Cirilo Marmolejo, [Los Angeles, CA.], Folklyric Records; Distributed by Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by Mariachi Coculense de Cirilo Marmolejo... Ay, la dive -- La canelera -- Mexico lucido -- La Pulquera -- Las gaviotas -- Blanca palomita -- El Becero -- La Cantinera -- El Torero -- La Guerita -- A Donde estara es a negra consentida -- Lupia -- Elenamorado --; SWF 88.7/D.8 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 1, Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by various artists... El relampago (Narcisso Martinez) -- Contrabandistas tequilero (Pedro Rocha y Lupe Martinez) -- Luz (El Ciego Melquiades) -- Per hay que triste (Lydia Mendoza) -- La Cucaracha (Orquesta Pajara) -- Izul -- La Indita Bonita (Banda Tipica Mazatlan) -- Que me gano con llorar (Trio San Antonio) -- Cancion mixteca (Los Donnenos) -- El muchacho llegre (Los Nortenos con Mariachi) -- El Guero Estrada (Ilegres de Teran) -- A punaladas (Hermanos Prado) -- Vete de mi (Los Gavilanes) -- El chicano (Los Nortenos de Nuevo Loredo) --; SWF 88.7/D.9 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 2, Folklyric Records; Distributed by Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Corridos, part one... Gregorio Cortez (Trovadores Regionales) -- Corrido de Joaquin Murrietta (Hermanos Sanchez and Linares) -- El Deportado (Hermanos Banuelos) -- Jesus Cadena (Pedro Rocha y Lupe Martinez) -- El Lavaplatos (Hermanos Banuelos) -- El Corrido de Texas (S. Ramos and D. Ramirez) -- Corrido Pensilvanue (Lupe Martinez and Pedro Roche) -- Corrido de Juan Reyna (Hermanos Banuelos) -- Suicidio de Juan Reyna (Nacho and Justine) --; SWF 88.7/D.10 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 3: Corridos, Part 2: 1929-1936, Folklyric Records; Distributed by Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Corridos, part two: 1929-1936... La tragedia de Oklahoma (Ramos and Ortega) -- Fidel Espinoza (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Corrido de las Hermanos Hernandez (Hmos. Sanchez and Linares) -- El huerfano (Trio Matamoros) -- Captain Charles Stevens (Pedro Rocha and Lupe Martinez) -- Corrido de los bootleggers (Francisco Montalvo and Indres Berlanga) -- Corrido de Bonifacie Torres (Hermanos Banuelos) -- Zenadia (Los Madrigadores) --; SWF 88.7/D.11 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 4: Norteño Acordeon, Part 1: The First recordings, Norteño Accordeon, Arhoolie/Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Norteno accordeon, volume one... The first recordings... La liebre ligera (Estanislado Salazar y Hermanos Mier) -- Adelita (Roberto Rodriguez y Clemente Mendoza) -- Flor marchita (Narciso Martinez) -- La Cucaracha (Flores y Montalvo) -- La bien polviada (Jesus Casiano) -- Los siete pasos (Bruno Villareal) -- Salvador (Narciso Martinez) -- Dispensa el arrempijon (Santiago Jimenez) -- La Nopalera (Santiago Jimenez) -- El zacatal (Jose Rodriguez) -- El Tecolote (Narciso Martinez) -- El Golfo (Lolo Cavazos) -- La Gardenia (Lolo Cavazos) -- La cascada (Bruno Villareal) -- Las perlas (Narciso Martinez) -- La peta cona (Jose Rodriguez) --; SWF 88.7/D.12 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 5: The String bands, Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Performed by various string bands... Cielito linda (Orquesta Colonial) -- La Cuarto milpas (Mariachi Rodriguez) -- Tamaulipecos (Trovadores Tamaulipecos) -- Pecor es nada (El Trio Alegre) -- Ojitos chinos y negros (Mariachi Acosta, Montoya, y Cruz) -- La Respingona (Santiago Morales) -- El poder del amor (El Trio Alegre) -- Adios amor mio (Orquestra Fronteriza) -- Panchita (El ciego melquiades) -- Mancornadora de mi corazon (Cuarteto Monterry) -- Marosovia (Los Alegres) -- Andale, vamos platicando (Medina River Boys) -- Bus care quien me consuele (Santos Guerrero y Quirino Garcia) -- El Jarabe Veracruzano (Andres Huesca y su Trio Huracen) -- Panchita (Lydia Mendoza y Familia) -- Se murio la curcaracha (Lydia Mendoz y Grupo) --; SWF 88.7/D.13 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 6: Cancioneros de Ayer - Part 1, Songsters from the past 1920's/1930's, 1977; Folklyric Records, p1977; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Indita mia (Pedro Rocha and Lupe Martinez) -- Traigo un sentimiente (Guzman and Hernandez) -- San Juan de Olua (Trio Luna) -- Una noche de luna (Cancioneros de los santos) -- La Madera (Gomez y Fierro) -- Un marinero en el golfo (Los Madrugadores) -- El Fronterizo (Gonzales and Rosales) -- Que importa al mundo (Los Madrugadores) -- De mi no te burles (Solis y Obregon) -- El barco costero (Gonzales and Rosales) -- Por debajo de los arboles (Ramos and Ramirez) -- Hijo de la paseada (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Bonita plan de la villa (Salas and Mendoza) -- Il para me en esa es quince (Guzman y Hernandez) --; SWF 88.7/D.14 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 7: Cancioneros de Ayer - Part 2, Songsters from the past 1920's/1930's, 1977; Folklyric Records, p1977; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Paloma de San Juan del Rio (Pedro Rocha and Lupe Martinez) -- Un despertar (Hernandez y Sifuentes) -- Carita de virgen (Luna and Delgado) -- El quelite (Luna and Delgado) -- Mi concha (Hermanos Banuelos) -- Cuarto palomitas blancas (Cortez and Gutierrez) -- Los barandales del puerte (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Mananitas Tapatias (Los Madrugadores) -- Yo me vine de mi tierra (Los Madrugadores) -- Ay! Que muchachos! (Hernandez and Sifuentes) -- Despierta mamasita (Hermanos Chavarria) -- El capiro (Guzman and Hernandez) -- El Vencido (Valdez and Flores) --; SWF 88.7/D.15 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 8: Cancioneros de Ayer - Part 3, Songsters from the past 1920's/1930's, 1977; Folklyric Records, p1977; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; La Modesta (Pedro Rocha and Lupe Martinez) -- Muchachas del vacilon (Flores and Valdez) -- El Buque de mas potencia (Guzman and Hernandez) -- El mucha cho alegre (Los Madrigadores) -- Yo en el mundo vivo (Luna and Montalvo) -- El favor que yo te pido (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Lagrimas lloro (Gaytan and Canti) -- Le pido al cielo (Ramirez and Equihua) -- El Capricho (Valdez and Gonzalez) -- Una noche serena y obscura (Rocha y Martinez) -- Pobre y pobre de mi (Valdez y Gonzalez) -- Dime cuanto has de querer (Ramon Jazo) -- Yo no espero (Lydia Mendoza y familia) --; SWF 88.7/D.16 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 9: Cancioneros de Ayer - Part 3, Songsters from the past 1920's/1930's, 1977; Folklyric Records, p1977; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Senorita cantinera (Gaylan and Cantu) -- Vive feliz (Ramirez y Equihua) -- Garcia y Zammarripa (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Yo fue el primero (Rocha y Martinez) -- Delgadina (Lydia Mendoza y Familia) -- La Sierra Mojada (Rocha y Martinez) -- Morena de ojos negras (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Esos enamorados (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Paloma mensajera (Rocha y Martinez) -- Prisionero de amor (Los Madrugadores) -- Ojitos negros (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Lola, Lola (Rodriguez y Montalvo) -- Tenia una negra (Rocha y Martinez) --; SWF 88.7/D.17 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 9: Cancioneros de Ayer - Part 3, Songsters from the past 1920's/1930's, 1977; Folklyric Records, p1977; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Senorita cantinera (Gaylan and Cantu) -- Vive feliz (Ramirez y Equihua) -- Garcia y Zammarripa (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Yo fue el primero (Rocha y Martinez) -- Delgadina (Lydia Mendoza y Familia) -- La Sierra Mojada (Rocha y Martinez) -- Morena de ojos negras (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Esos enamorados (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Paloma mensajera (Rocha y Martinez) -- Prisionero de amor (Los Madrugadores) -- Ojitos negros (Hermanos Chavarria) -- Lola, Lola (Rodriguez y Montalvo) -- Tenia una negra (Rocha y Martinez) --; SWF 88.7/D.17 (12in.) - Access DVD
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 10: Narciso Martinez, "El Huracan del valle", Martinez, Narciso and Santiago Almeida, 1978; Folklyric Records, 1978; Distributed by Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; La Chicarronera -- El Tronconal -- Viva mojarra -- Luzita -- La Enagua almidonada -- Robstown -- Poquito de todo -- Piedras negras -- El amor de panchita -- El Colorado -- Muchacha bonita -- Delfo -- California -- Recuerdo -- Labios de coral -- Lola -- Ojos negros --; SWF 88.7/D.18 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 11: El Ciego melquides, "The Blind fiddler", Folklyric Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Aqui esta tu amor -- A mi amor -- Muchacha modernas -- Quisiera llorar -- Viva laredo -- Impossible -- Cholulu -- Concha -- Isabel -- Jalisco nunca -- Los aeroplanos -- Andrea -- Te espero a fuero -- La Vividita -- Manuelita --; SWF 88.7/D.19 (12in.)
- Texas-Mexican border music, Vol. 12: Norteño acordeon, Part 2: San Antonio, the 1940's and 50's, Norteño acordeon, Folklyric Records; Distributed by Arhoolie Records; 1 sound disc, analog, [33 1/3 rpm], 12 in.; Viva sequin (Santiago Jimenez y Sus Valedoves) -- Chabelita (Santiago Jimenez y Sus Valedoves) -- La Cubanita (Santiago Jimenez y Sus Valedoves) -- Cada vez que ca la tarde (Santiago Jimenez y Sus Valedoves) -- La pied rera (Santiago Jimenez y Sus Valedoves) -- Negra traicion (Los Caminantes) -- La Complicada (Los Caminantes)_ -- Siembre hace frio (Los Caminantes) -- Amor me falta (Conjunto Longoria) -- Pobre mujer (Conjunto Longoria) -- De San Antonio a Michigan (El Gallito) -- Si tu te vas (Conjunto Longoria) -- Monterrey (Trio San Antonio) -- No hay remedio (Trio San Antonio) -- Un recuerdo quedo (Trio San Antonio) -- Michula (Trio San Antonio) --; SWF 88.7/D.20 (12in.)